Bernoulli refined the idea of expectation.
تلك فكرة محسنة برنولي .
He was focused on a method of accurately estimating
كان تركز على طريقة من بدقة تقدير
the unknown probability of some event based on
المجهول الاحتمالات بناءا على بعض الحدث
the number of times the event occurs in independent trials.
عدد مرات الحدث تحدث في التجارب المستقلة .
He uses a simple example.
وهو يستخدم مثال بسيط .
Suppose that without your knowledge,
لنفترض انك , بدون معرفة
3,000 light pebbles and 2,000 dark pebbles
3000 الضوء والظلام الحصى 2000 الحصى
are hidden in an urn, and that to determine
خفية في urn , وهذا لتحديد
the ratio of white versus black by experiment,
نسبة مقابل الابيض بالتجربة , سوداء
you draw one pebble after another,
ترسم واحدة بعد الاخرى , حصاه
with replacement, and note how many times
وبالاستبدال ملاحظة كم مرة
a white pebble is drawn versus black.
سحب يعد بالابيض والاسود .
He went on to prove that the expected value
ذهب لاثبات ان القيمة المتوقعة
of white versus black observations
من الملاحظات الابيض والاسود
will converge on the actual ratio
ستتقارب على نسبة الحقيقية
as the number of trials increases,
كلما زاد عدد التجارب ,
known as the weak law of large numbers.
قانون الضعيفة من المعروف باعداد كبيرة .
He concluded by saying, "If observations
قد خلصت بالقول , &quot; اذا الملاحظات
"of all events be continued for the entire infinity,
لان كل الاحداث في &quot; لكل ما لا نهاية ,
"it will be noticed that everything in the world
لاحظت انه سيكون &quot; كل شيء في العالم
"is governed by precise ratios
&quot; مسيرة بنسب دقيقة
"and a constant law of change."
&quot; وثابتة من تغيير القوانين . &quot;
This idea was quickly extended
هذه الفكرة كانت بسرعة الممتدة
as it was noticed that not only
وكان هذا ليس فقط لاحظ
did things converge on an expected average,
هل على الاشياء تتقارب في المتوسط , متوقع
but the probability of variation away from averages
لكن احتماليه الاختلاف من نسبة
also follow a familiar, underlying shape,
وايضا تتبع الشكل الاساسي , تعرفون ,
or distribution.
او التوزيع .
A great example of this is Francis Galton's bean machine.
هذا هو مثال رائع انها الة الفاصوليا فرانسيس جالتون .
Imagine each collision as a single independent event,
تخيل التصادم ككل واحد , المستقل
such as a coin flip.
مثل قلب العملة .
After 10 collisions or events,
بعد 10 او الاحداث , اصطدام
the bean falls into a bucket representing
وفي الدلو تمثيل الفاصوليا
the ratio of left versus right deflection,
نسبة deflection مقابل الايمن والايسر
or heads versus tails.
او الرؤوس مقابل الكتابة .
This overall curvature, known as the binomial distribution,
هذا العام , معروفة انحناء كbinomial التوزيع ,
appears to be an ideal form
يبدو شكل مثالي
as it kept appearing everywhere
كذلك بالظهور في كل مكان
any time you looked at the variation
نظرت الى اي اختلاف الوقت
of a large number of random trials.
من عدد كبير من التجارب العشوائية .
It seems the average fate of these events
يبدو متوسط قدر من هذه الاحداث
is somehow predetermined, known today
اليوم , ما هو معروف المحددة سلفا
as the central limit theorem.
كعبارة الحد المركزية .